Menna Rihan

I'm a frontend developer. I'm specialised in creating pixel-perfect seamless designs. I have very good research skills. I'm very knowledgeable about ChatGPT, Copilot, and other AI tools. I'm a quick learner and always ready for new challenges.

Certificates

- Frontend Development fellowship -Women Techsters Tech4Dev.
- Front-end Web Development scholarship Egyptian Council UN Women
- Web Development -Professional Nanodegree Udacity -ITIDA
- Intro to Web Development GOMYCODE

Work Experience

Frontend Web Developer

June 2024 - Present

- Developing responsive web designs that ensure seamless user experiences across devices of all sizes.
- Building functional and interactive web applications with a focus on performance and usability.
- Fetching and integrating data from RESTful APIs to create dynamic, data-driven user interfaces.
- Optimizing web applications for speed and scalability, using modern web technologies like React, Next.js, and Tailwind CSS.
- Collaborating with designers and backend developers to deliver well-structured, efficient code that meets project specifications.
- Ensuring cross-browser compatibility and conducting thorough browser testing for smooth performance.

Founder & Owner - Rihan Store

Jan 2018 - Dec 2022

- E-commerce Management: Created and managed a Shopify website, including theme editing and account management.
- Social Media Management: Handled social media accounts, including photography, content creation, and customer support.
- Sales and Customer Service: Managed the offline store, responsible for sales and customer interactions.
- Content Creation: Produced high-quality photography and engaging content for online and offline marketing.
- Supplier Management: Searched for and contacted suppliers and print houses.

Food Photographer/ Stylist - Freelance

Dec 2014 - Present

- Art direction.
- Prop styling.
- Photo editing.

Contact

New Cairo, Egypt 01008878175 menna1986@live.com Portfolio Photography Portfolio Github Linkedin

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- React Js
- Next Js
- Github
- Art Direction
- Design
- Photography

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Arabic (Native)

Executive Secretary & HR Assistant - AB Care for Medical Supplies

Oct 2011 - Oct 2012

- Writing letters.
- Handling hotels reservations.
- Translating any required document from Arabic into English and vice versa.
- Receiving & filtering CVs.
- Handling telephone interviews for candidates.
- Managing interviews process & setting the applications and tests for candidates.
- Scanning and filtering cvs.
- Doing researches regarding anything required by the HR department.

Freelance Translator - Tarjamat

Feb 2010 - Mar 2011

• Translating all kinds of documents from Arabic to English and vice versa.

Executive Secretary & HR Assistant - The Organization of Islamic Cooperation OIC

Jul 2008 - Dec 2010

- Translating any required document from Arabic into English and vice versa.
- Receiving & filtering CVs.
- Handling telephone interviews for candidates.
- Managing interviews process & setting the applications and tests for candidates.
- Managing the attendance process for the employees.
- Posting job vacancies advertisements.
- Scanning and filtering cvs.
- Assisting in the hiring process
- Doing researches regarding anything required by the HR department.

Educational Background

B.A. Alsun, English Language and Literature, General 2004 - 2008